Minjoo Cho

+49 174 6231773 minjoolisa.cho@gmail.com Portfolio(pdf) Personal Webpage LinkedIn

OBJECTIVE

I am a polymathic creative technologist who designs and prototype ideas for connected devices to enhance the experience between users and products, within product networks, and products to the world.

I bring technical concepts that augments product experience based on deep affinity to humanity, and draw the experience with technical toolkits.

SKILLS

IoT Proof-of-concept prototyping

- · Embedded: Arduino, RaspberryPi
- Network protocols: web socket, I2C, Serial, SPI
- Serverless Backend: Firebase, AWS IoT Core, DynamoDB
- Server Backend: Python-Flask, Node. js, JQuery, MongoDB
- Frontend: HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Processing, P5.js
- Mobile Native: Android SDK

Emerging Technology

- Machine Learning Libraries: Object Recognition, Magenta-Polyphonic RNN
- · AR/VR: AR Core, Unity-Vuforia
- Computer Vision Libraries: OpenCV, Pygame

Design Tools

- 3D Tools: Rhinoceros, Solidworks, Fusion260, Keyshot
- 2D Tools: Adobe Series (Illustrator, InDesign, Premier Pro)

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent, C2)
- · Korean (Native)
- · Japanese (Fluent, C2)
- Chinese (Intermediate, C1)
- German (Basics, B1)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Creative Technologist, Indeed Innovation

Hamburg, Germany

May, 2017 - Present

<u>Indeed Innovation</u> is an innovation firm implementing a new product or service strategy based on a human-centered design approach. My main roles include: Fast PoC Technical Prototyping for IoT products

- Liaison of developers and designers throughout the conceptual stage of the project and help implementing proof-of-concept prototype to validate the generated ideas.
- Client-facing role: project pitch, design workshop, development progress reports Interactive Installation development / demonstration
- Full implementation of interactive installation from concept development to delivery
- Concept development, full technical implementation (SW, HW, System integration), demonstration guideline

Creative Strategist, Samsung Creative Lab

Suwon, South Korea

Suwon, South Korea

Jun 2013 — Oct 2014

<u>Samsung Creative Lab</u> is a Samsung's incubation program for Samsung employees to incubate creative ideas into real project. My role in the team included:

- Project Proposal: Proposed the winning idea to gain entry in C-Lab
- Product Strategy and development: product features definition, fast-prototyping (Android SW), in charging of user research with the hearing-impaired community
- · Regular progress report to the C-level representatives

Product Manager, Samsung Electronics HQ

Jan 2011 — Dec 2014

My main role as a product manager in the product strategy team in Samsung Mobile division included:

- Responsible for Samsung Galaxy Tablet Series, and Google Nexus 10
- Product Life Cycle Management: solving procedural issues during the entire product life cycle from the development stage to the end of production
- Regular VP/C-level issue reports on the project status
- Product strategy building for the sustainable sales growth, defining USPs for the market communication

EDUCATION

M.S in Industrial Design, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2015 — Feb 2017

- · Mater's thesis: Calm Automaton, A DIY Toolkit for Ambient Displays
- A previous research member of <u>myDesignLAB</u> (Prof. Daniel Saakes)
- Full year scholarship: National Science and Technology Scholarship

B.S in Electrical Engineering, KAIST

Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2006 — Feb 2011

- Major in Electrical Engineering and minor in Business Economics
- Full year scholarship: National Science and Technology Scholarship